{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "1. Surface plasmon resonance is used to study which type of molecular interactions?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Protein-protein",
        "b": "Protein-DNA",
        "c": "DNA-protein",
        "d": "All of the above                         "
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. Which of the following materials is commonly used to coat the SPR sensor chip? ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Silicon",
        "b": "Gold",
        "c": "Plastic",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    
    {
      "question": "3. The detection unit of the SPR sensors detects which of the following parameters? ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Conductivity",
        "b": "Absorbance",
        "c": "Refractive index changes",
        "d": "Pressure"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "4. When there is an increase in the refractive index of the medium in contact to the metal surface, the SPR angle ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Remains constant",
        "b": "Increases",
        "c": "Decreases ",
        "d": "Fluctuates"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The primary advantage of using SPR for protein-protein interaction is ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "High sensitivity",
        "b": "Real-time monitoring",
        "c": "Label-free detection",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "6. The RU in the SPR sensorgram stands for ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Resonance Unit",
        "b": "Response Unit",
        "c": "Refraction unit",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Which phase of the SPR experiment depicts the injection of an interacting molecule (analyte) over the immobilized ligand? ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Association phase",
        "b": "Equilibration phase",
        "c": "Dissociation phase",
        "d": "Regeneration phase"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "8. The binding kinetics between two proteins depends on which of the following parameters? ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Changes in absorbance",
        "b": "Changes in mass",
        "c": "Changes in magnetic field",
        "d": "Changes in fluorescence intensity"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "9. What is the relation between the dissociation constant (KD) and binding affinity between two interacting proteins? ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Inversely proportional",
        "b": "Directly proportional",
        "c": "Logarithmically relation",
        "d": "Not correlated"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "10. Covalent immobilization of ligand on the sensor chip is achieved using ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Amine",
        "b": "Aldehyde coupling",
        "c": "Both a & b",
        "d": "High affinity capture"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
  ]
}
